Taft, Philip Papers 5541
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series II. Research/Subject Files
  - World War II - Defense, 1936-1942 (Box 14, Folder 12cont.)
    letter from President, AFL Building and Construction Trades Department to all affiliated unions with confidential letter of agreement between the Department and government agencies engaged in defense construction re no strikes, minimum wage and overtime, apprentices, Board of Review, July 23, 1941; minutes of the Fourth Meeting of AFL National Defense Committee, July 30, 1941, 3 pages; correspondence between Office of Production Management, War Department and AFL Building and Construction Trades Department re labor policy, August 1, 1941, 11 pages; "Organization and Executive Personnel, Office of Production Management, August 1941 (Showing Previous Affiliation)" by Research and Information Service, AFL, 15 pages; "Agenda of the 5th Meeting of the AFL National Defense Committee, August 27, 1941"; "National Defense Mediation Board," list of public, management and labor representatives, n.d.; "Failure to Spread Defense Contracts" with map, "Distribution of Prime National Defense Contract Awards by Industrial Areas," April 30, 1941, AFL Research and Information Service; "Agenda, Sixth Meeting of the AFL National Defense Committee, September 17, 1941," with attached minutes of fifth meeting, description of "Supply, Priorities and Allocations Board", orders of "Office of Production Management from August 25 to September 14, 1941", "Office of Price Administration", "Office of Civilian Defense", and "A Comprehensive Program of Social Insurance"; "The Buffalo Plan," brief description of compensation plan for displaced workers at Chevrolet plant, with analysis of broader applications, September 17, 1941; "War Production Board Management-Labor Council," 6 page manuscript re organization, establishment of labor-management committees, n.d.; "Minutes of the Seventh Meeting of the AFL National Defense Committee ... November 12, 1941" re price controls, agricultural exemption, 3 pages, and press release, November 15, 1941; minutes of the AFL Executive Council re no-strike pledge, December 15, 1941; re resolutions proposed by CIO, AFL, Employers and Joint AFL-CIO committee at Employers-Labor Conference, December 18, 1941, 8 pages; AFL Defense Committee Agenda, December 31, 1941; "Advisory Committee," 10 page manuscript alleging pro-CIO bias of Office of Production Management's Labor Division, C. December 31, 1941; form letters; notes.
  - World War II - Defense Communications Board, 1942 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    Two page statement by communications workers' unions, approved for submission to the Defense Communications Board by the Board's Labor Advisory Committee, n.d.; "Confidential Minutes of the Joint Meeting of the Industry Advisory Committee and the Labor Advisory Committee of the Defense Committee Board," January 7, 1942, 11 pages; "Board of War Communications," 5 page description with list of committee members, c. 1942.
  - World War II - National Service Act, 1944 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    Form letters, statement by AFL President Green, opposing Act.
  - World War II - Office of Civilian Defense, 1942 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    "Office of Civilian Defense," 4 page manuscript, 1942.
  - World War II - War Labor Board, 1942-1945 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    Two unsigned typescripts, "National War Labor Board," one with pencil notation "1943", the other n.d., 9 pages and 6 pages, respectively; "The Anti-Inflation Program," AFL statement re wages and inflation in war production, copied from AFL Weekly News Service, July 12, 1942; press release announcing Executive Order fixing ceilings on rents and formerly exempt agricultural commodities, October 3, 1942, 6 pages; "Text of AFL Members' Statement on Wage Squeeze," demanding modification of President Roosevelt's Executive Order freezing wages, April 1943, 5 pages; press release, "Statement of Mr. George Meany, Secretary-Treasurer, AFL, to the Special Panel of the National War Labor Board, on the Little Steel Formula," urging higher cost-of-living wage raises, April 4, 1944, 16 pages; minutes of AFL Executive Council re War Labor Board, August 14, 1943 and July 27, 1945; "National War Labor Board Wage Stabilization General Orders and Interpretations - Under Executive Order 9250, Executive Order 9328 and the Regulations of the Director of Economic Stabilization," November 1944, 88 pages; two issues of the AFL Weekly News Service, 1943 and 1944; many notes.
  - World War II - War Labor Board - Correspondence, 1941-1944 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    Letters, mainly to AFL President Green from various State Federations of Labor, September 1942.
  - World War II - War Labor Board - Regional, 1942-1945 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    "Protests Received Regarding Nominations for Appointment of AFL Representatives to Serve on Regional War Labor Boards," July and August 1944, 7 pages; correspondence between AFL President Green and Chairman, National War Labor Board, re AFL representatives for regional councils, October-November 1942; related correspondence between AFL President Green and other AFL regional officials, June-July 1944; letter from President Green instructing withdrawal of AFL organizers from regional War Labor Boards because of adverse decisions of Boards, constraints on organizers' time, August 11, 1944; letters from President to labor members of New York and Dallas Regional War Labor Boards re new Stabilization Division nominations, November 20-21, 1945.
  - Youth Movement, 1935 (Box 14, Folder 19)
- Series III. PUBLICATIONS (PUBLISHED AND UNPUBLISHED MANUSCRIPTS)
  - AFL-CIO Internal Disputes Plan (Restricted). (Box 15, Folder 1-2)
  - American Labor Violence - Its Causes.... (Box 15, Folder 3-4)
  - Associations Not for Profit (Restricted). (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Bargaining and Protest Strikes (Restricted). (Box 15, Folder 6-7)
  - Dubinsky, David. (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Fair Trials For Union Members (Restricted). (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Labor History and the Labor Movement. (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Labor in the First Three Decades. (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Landrum-Griffen (Restricted). (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Murray, Philip. (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - On the Origins of Business Unionism. (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Organized Labor in American History. (Box 15, Folder 15-27)
  - Rank and File Unrest (Restricted). (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Rights of Union Members. (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Seventy Years of Life and Labor (Introduction). (Box 15, Folder 36)
  - Structural Unemployment. (Box 15, Folder 37)
  - Trends in the Present Day Labor Movement (Restricted). (Box 15, Folder 38)
  - The Unions, Collective Bargaining and Older Workers. (Box 15, Folder 39)
  - Miscellaneous Manuscripts (untitled, etc.). (Box 15, Folder 40)
- Series IV. IMPARTIAL UMPIRE DECISIONS OF AFL-CIO INTERNAL DISPUTES PLAN
  - Decisions by Taft, Impartial Umpire (Box 15, Folder 41-47)
- Series V. LECTURE NOTES
  - Lecture notes (Box 16, Folder 1-14)
  - Reading lists (Box 16, Folder 15)
- Series VI. MISCELLANEOUS
  - Report re Rhode Island Department of Economic Security by Taft. (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Project - Bureau of Labor-Management Reports - Department of Labor (Box 16, Folder 17-33)
    Includes completed forms re labor organizations and several issues of Office of Labor- Management and Welfare Pension Reports Bulletins
  - Miscellaneous Bibliographies (Box 16, Folder 34)
  - Photograph. (Box 16, Folder 35)
  - Miscellaneous Publications and Miscellaneous Index Cards (Box 16, Folder 36-37)
  - Philip Taft Memorial Service - December 10, 1976, Audio cassette tape (Box 17.1)
    Copy 1
  - Philip Taft Memorial Service - December 10, 1976, Audio cassette tape (Box 17.2)
    Copy 2
  - May 1974 - Labor History meeting in Washington, D.C., Audio cassette tape (Box 18.1)
  - May 1974 - Labor History meeting in Washington, D.C., Audio cassette tape (Box 18.2)
  - Philip Taft - Interview - Brown University Radio & TV, Audio cassette tape (Box 19.1)
  - Philip Taft - Interview - Brown University Radio & TV, Audio cassette tape (Box 19.2)